<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="//purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="//wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="//purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="//www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="//purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="//purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News - Discount Landlord</title>
	<atom:link href="//www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news</link>
	<description>News - Discount Landlord</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 08:35:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>//wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<xhtml:meta xmlns:xhtml="//www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex" />
		<item>
		<title>Landlords urged to look out for unauthorised subletting</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/landlords-urged-to-look-out-for-unauthorised-subletting/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/landlords-urged-to-look-out-for-unauthorised-subletting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 08:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5900</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Illegal sub-letting is on the rise due to escalating rents and a shortage of affordable property, say experts. &#160; Last month Oxford Council held a two-month amnesty, in the hopes that tenants who were illegally subletting their homes would hand back the keys to the properties. &#160; The amnesty campaign also warned that illegal [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5901" alt="Discount Landlord news " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/16th-Oct.jpg" width="435" height="305" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Illegal sub-letting</strong> is on the rise due to escalating rents and a shortage of affordable property, say experts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Last month Oxford Council held a <strong>two-month amnesty</strong>, in the hopes that tenants who were illegally subletting their homes would hand back the keys to the properties.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The amnesty campaign also warned that illegal subletting is now a <strong>criminal offence</strong> and could be punishable by a fine, or even a prison sentence in severe cases.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-5900"></span></p>
<p><strong>Ghost tenants </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is estimated that there are now <strong>3.3 million ‘ghost tenants’</strong> living in the UK – as many as one in every 10 rental homes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>According to a report last year, almost half of residential letting agencies found multiple occupants living in a home unofficially after checking their properties.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is important that you check your properties regularly (giving the tenants at least 24 hours notice) to make sure that only those named on the <strong>tenancy agreement</strong> are living there. Keep an eye out for signs that somebody is living full time on a sofa or in a study room, for example, advises Discount Landlord.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>If you are suspicious that a tenant is subletting:</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Look out for additional bedding such as sleeping bags and pillows; suitcases and rucksacks; and extra toothbrushes.</li>
<li>The tenants will be hiding evidence of extra tenants, so look out for additional clothing and shoes, excessive rubbish for the number of registered tenants.</li>
<li>Before taking on a new tenant, make sure you carry out a thorough reference to ensure you know who your tenant really is and that they have a good rental history.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/our_products/residential_landlord">Landlords</a> – protect your rental income with <a href="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/our_products/protecting_your_investment">Legal Expenses &amp; Rent Guarantee</a> Insurance from <strong>Discount Landlord</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/landlords-urged-to-look-out-for-unauthorised-subletting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>First-time buyers under 40 to get 20% off under Tory plan</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/first-time-buyers-under-40-to-get-20-off-under-tory-plan/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/first-time-buyers-under-40-to-get-20-off-under-tory-plan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 08:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5893</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; First-time buyers in England under the age of 40 could buy a house at 20% below the market rate if the Conservatives are re-elected David Cameron has pledged. &#160; The Conservative leader said a future government led by him would build 100,000 new homes for such people. &#160; They would be built on &#8216;brownfield&#8217; [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5894" alt="Home Insurance Quote " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/179692092.jpg" width="435" height="290" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>First-time buyers in England <strong>under the age of 40</strong> could buy a house at <strong>20% below the market rate</strong> if the Conservatives are re-elected David Cameron has pledged.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Conservative leader said a future government led by him would build <strong>100,000 new homes</strong> for such people.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>They would be built on &#8216;brownfield&#8217; land already identified for development and exempt from some taxes, he said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-5893"></span></p>
<p>Unveiling the pledge – an extension of the <strong>Help to Buy</strong> mortgage scheme – Mr Cameron said the Conservatives wanted more young people to “achieve the dream” of owning their own home.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“I want young people who work hard, who do the right thing, to be able to buy a home of their own. So these starter homes will be sold at <strong>20%</strong> less than the market value.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“They can’t be bought by foreigners, they can’t be bought by buy-to-let landlords, and they can’t be flipped round in a quick sale. They can only be bought by hard working people under the age of 40.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The starter homes plan would apply only to England, whereas Help to Buy is UK-wide.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>That scheme entails the government offering a <strong>20% equity loan</strong> to buyers of new-build properties.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you have recently purchased your first home then make sure you protect it with <a href="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/our_products/home_insurance">home insurance</a> from <strong>Discount Landlord</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/first-time-buyers-under-40-to-get-20-off-under-tory-plan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Labour plans would be bad news for rented sector, says RLA</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/labour-plans-would-be-bad-news-for-rented-sector-says-rla/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/labour-plans-would-be-bad-news-for-rented-sector-says-rla/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 08:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5884</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Labour’s plan for new controls in the private rented sector (PRS) would “critically undermine” landlords, says the Residential Landlords Association (RLA). &#160; Labour announced a number of new measures at last week’s party conference, but the RLA says that the extra regulations for the sector would significantly damage the only sector that is boosting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5887" alt="9th Oct" src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/9th-Oct.jpg" width="507" height="338" /></p>
<p>Labour’s plan for new controls in the private rented sector (PRS) would “<strong>critically undermine</strong>” landlords, says the Residential Landlords Association (RLA).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Labour announced a number of <strong>new measures</strong> at last week’s party conference, but the RLA says that the extra regulations for the sector would significantly damage the only sector that is boosting the supply of places to live.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Nearly <strong>60%</strong> of the UK’s housing stock created since 1986 has been in the private rented sector, says the RLA.</p>
<p><span id="more-5884"></span></p>
<p>Over five million new dwellings have been created in the UK between 1986 and 2012,<strong> 57%</strong> of which have been private homes to rent, according to the RLA’s analysis of figures released by the Department for Communities and Local Government.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Last week, shadow ministers announced plans for the following, should Labour come to power:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>• A national register of landlords.</p>
<p>• Rent controls – capping the amount of rent landlords can charge in certain areas.</p>
<p>• Banning so-called ‘revenge evictions’.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“The figures show that private landlords are the largest single investor group in the UK housing market. Without the increase in rented dwellings we have seen, the current housing crisis would be more like an Armageddon,” says RLA chairman Alan Ward.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/labour-plans-would-be-bad-news-for-rented-sector-says-rla/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Being a landlord is more stressful than it used to be, survey suggests</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/being-a-landlord-is-more-stressful-than-it-used-to-be-survey-suggests/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/being-a-landlord-is-more-stressful-than-it-used-to-be-survey-suggests/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 08:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landlords and Tenants]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5877</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is becoming an increasingly stressful business being a UK landlord, with over half using their holidays to sort out issues, new research has revealed. &#160; 67% said that they were more stressed than 12 months ago and some 25% are finding being a landlord more stressful than they had imagined, according to a new survey [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5879" alt="Residential Landlord Insurance" src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/7th-Oct.jpg" width="435" height="289" /></p>
<p>It is becoming an <strong>increasingly stressful</strong> business being a UK landlord, with over half using their holidays to sort out issues, new research has revealed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>67%</strong> said that they were more stressed than 12 months ago and some <strong>25%</strong> are finding being a landlord more stressful than they had imagined, according to a new survey by UK Landlord Tax.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>53%</strong> of landlords use up to <strong>20%</strong> of their annual leave sorting out property issues, the survey showed.</p>
<p><span id="more-5877"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>On call</b></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>46%</strong> of landlords spent up to <strong>20 hours a year</strong> on phone calls, sorting out house repairs, maintenance, and negotiating with agents and tenants, according to the survey.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Late rent payments</strong> (<strong>58%</strong>),<strong> funding property maintenance</strong> and repairs (<strong>40%</strong>) and <strong>tax worries</strong> (38%), also contributed to the stress.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Those who had been landlords for <strong>10 years or more</strong> said that they felt under the least pressure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Expat landlords</b></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Expat landlords were the most stressed according to the survey, with many concerned about how the potential changes to personal allowance entitlement would affect them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other concerns for all landlords included <strong>unoccupied properties and void periods (35%)</strong>, not having enough time to deal with issues at the property due to work constraints (<strong>28%</strong>) and expensive agency fees (15%).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>Landlords – don’t stress out about your <a href="//https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/our_products/residential_landlord">insurance</a>, come straight to Discount Landlord for a quick quote and hassle-free cover! </i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/being-a-landlord-is-more-stressful-than-it-used-to-be-survey-suggests/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Rent to Buy Scheme to help first-time buyers onto the ladder</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/new-rent-to-buy-scheme-to-help-first-time-buyers-onto-the-housing-ladder-2/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/new-rent-to-buy-scheme-to-help-first-time-buyers-onto-the-housing-ladder-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landlords and Tenants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Property Market Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5870</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; A new scheme to help first-time buyers onto the housing ladder has been announced by the Communities Secretary, Eric Pickles. &#160; The scheme will invite housing associations and other providers to bid for a share of £400 million in low-cost loans to build up to 10,000 one and two bedroom new homes between 2015 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5872" alt="Landlord Insurance " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/513566869-resized.jpg" width="435" height="326" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A new scheme to help <strong>first-time buyers</strong> onto the housing ladder has been announced by the Communities Secretary, Eric Pickles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The scheme will invite housing associations and other providers to bid for a share of <strong>£400 million</strong> in low-cost loans to build up to <strong>10,000</strong> one and two bedroom new homes between 2015 and 2018.  Half of the scheme budget will be allocated to London due to the acute shortage of affordable property in the capital.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-5870"></span></p>
<p><strong>First refusal </strong></p>
<p>Landlords must make the properties available for rent a price below the market value for a minimum of seven years, after which the tenant will have first refusal to buy the property.  The idea is that the initial period of reduced rent will give the resident the opportunity to save for a deposit in order to purchase the property.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If the home is sold, the housing association will have the option to use any profits to build more affordable homes in the area or, if the tenant is unable to buy the property, the property is simply rented again at the reduced rate.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alongside Help to Buy and Right to Buy, this new scheme is part of a broader £23 billion affordable homes programme for 2015 to 2018.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Commenting on the scheme, London mayor Boris Johnson said: “Through this exciting new fund, we hope to provide thousands of brand new homes many years sooner than would otherwise be possible and make them available to rent at below market rates for hardworking Londoners.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Mixed reaction </strong></p>
<p>However responses to the scheme have been mixed with Matt Hutchinson, director of flat-sharing website SpareRoom.co.uk saying: “It is good in theory; the reality, however, is that even 10,000 homes won’t scratch the surface of a chronic supply problem that is severely impacting renters hoping to get onto the property ladder, particularly in London.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/new-rent-to-buy-scheme-to-help-first-time-buyers-onto-the-housing-ladder-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Labour plans rent caps and ban on agents&#8217; fees if they come to power</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/labour-plans-rent-caps-and-ban-on-agents-fees-if-they-come-to-power/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/labour-plans-rent-caps-and-ban-on-agents-fees-if-they-come-to-power/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 08:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landlords and Tenants]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5852</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; The Labour Party reaffirmed controversial plans to reform the private sector at a party conference last week. &#160; MP Hilary Benn vowed to mend the ‘broken’ housing market, calling for three-year tenancy agreements as standard, a ban on excessive rent increases, and a ban on letting agents’ fees to tenants, if the party comes to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5854" alt="Rentguard Insurance " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/30th-Sept.jpg" width="394" height="326" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The <strong>Labour</strong> <strong>Party</strong> reaffirmed controversial plans to reform the private sector at a party conference last week.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>MP Hilary Benn</strong> vowed to mend the ‘broken’ housing market, calling for <strong>three-year tenancy agreements</strong> as standard, a ban on excessive rent increases, and a <strong>ban on letting agents’ fees</strong> to tenants, if the party comes to power.</p>
<p><span id="more-5852"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“Young people are doing all they can to save, but knowing that their dream of owning a home is moving further and further out of reach. So they end up renting, and often find themselves paying off someone else’s mortgage, rather than one on a home of their own,” said Benn.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Benn also said that if Labour came to power it work with councils so that they can build more council houses.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Longer tenancies </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the topic of introducing longer rental contracts as standard, Benn said: “They probably have a short term tenancy and worry that the rent may jump up, even if they get a new contract. And if their children are about to start primary school, what kind of security and stability is there if they may be forced to move away from friends and neighbours next year?”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“We all hear these stories, but this government doesn’t get it. Well we do – and that’s why we are determined to introduce three year tenancies; to put a ceiling on rent increases; to scrap lettings agent fees for tenants; and to build at least 200,000 homes a year by the end of the next Parliament,” he added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/labour-plans-rent-caps-and-ban-on-agents-fees-if-they-come-to-power/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flats best UK performer over last 10 years, new research shows</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/homeowners/home-insurance/flats-were-best-performers-in-the-uk-over-last-10-years-new-research-shows/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/homeowners/home-insurance/flats-were-best-performers-in-the-uk-over-last-10-years-new-research-shows/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 08:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Buy to Let Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Insurance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5846</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Flat prices in the UK have risen by more than twice the average for all properties in the last decade, new research shows. &#160; According to research from Halifax Building Society, the average price of a flat in the UK has risen by nearly £51,000 or £425 per month, from £151,172 in 2004 to £208,169 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5847" alt="Diiscount Landlord " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/25th-Sept.jpg" width="435" height="290" /></p>
<p>Flat prices in the UK have risen by more than <strong>twice the average</strong> for all properties in the last decade, new research shows.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>According to research from Halifax Building Society, the average price of a flat in the UK has risen by nearly <strong>£51,000</strong> or <strong>£425 per month</strong>, from <strong>£151,172</strong> in <strong>2004</strong> to <strong>£208,169</strong> today, with much of this rise due to soaring flat prices in London.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The average price of a flat has increased <strong>32%</strong> &#8211; more than double the <strong>15%</strong> rise for all residential properties over the same period. Detached homes at <strong>12%</strong> and bungalows at <strong>13%</strong>, have recorded the smallest rises over the past 10 years.</p>
<p><span id="more-5846"></span></p>
<p>Flats represent a relatively high proportion of the property market in London and it is the performance in the capital which can largely be attributed to the nationwide rise.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Elsewhere, terraced homes have been the best performing property type, showing biggest average  price rises in the North West, Yorkshire and the Humber, West Midlands, East Midlands and East Anglia.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In terms of volume semi-detached and terraced homes remained the most popular types of property purchased over the past ten years, representing 60% of all home sales in 2014; up from 56% in 2004.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Semi-detached homes have risen steadily in popularity for first time buyers, accounting for 29% of purchases over the past ten years.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“There has been a significant increase in the number of first time buyers since 2010 compared with a modest decline in the number of those moving home. This difference is reflected in a bigger rise in prices over the past five years for those property types that are most popular with first time buyers,” says Martin Ellis, housing economist at the Halifax.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>At </i><em><strong>Discount Landlord</strong></em><i> we provide insurance for a large range of flats, including purpose built, HMOs and those of non-standard construction. </i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/homeowners/home-insurance/flats-were-best-performers-in-the-uk-over-last-10-years-new-research-shows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Survey reveals opposition to big housing developments in UK</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/survey-reveals-opposition-to-big-housing-developments-in-uk/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/survey-reveals-opposition-to-big-housing-developments-in-uk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 08:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With general agreement that a major uplift in new home building is crucial to resolution of the UK’s housing crisis, half of the population would oppose a major house building programme if it was in their immediate neighbourhood, a survey has found. Some 49% of Britons would be opposed to building more than 300 properties [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5844" alt="Discount Landlord News " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/23rd-Sept.jpg" width="539" height="317" /></p>
<p>With general agreement that a major uplift in new home building is crucial to resolution of the UK’s housing crisis, <strong>half of the population would oppose a major house building programme</strong> if it was in their immediate</p>
<p>neighbourhood, a survey has found.</p>
<p>Some <strong>49%</strong> of Britons would be opposed to building more than<strong> 300 properties</strong> in their neighbourhood and <strong>53%</strong> are anti-developments of <strong>100</strong> and <strong>299</strong> properties, according to their Property Tracker survey from the Building Societies</p>
<p>Association (BSA).</p>
<p><span id="more-5842"></span></p>
<p>But when asked how much of the UK they believe should be ‘urban’, which is defined as housing, gardens, train lines and parks, nine out of 10 said more than 10% of the country should be developed when currently just <strong>7%</strong> of the country is.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The majority of Britons are willing to support developments of one to 10 properties being built in their local area.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Against that, the research also shows that Britons are increasingly open to the types of properties they want to live in and want greater diversity in the types of properties and tenures available to them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>One in five people say they would be open to buying a shared ownership property, living in an off the shelf kit home, living in a converted retail or office space and even renting long term.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>And despite the fact that less than <strong>10%</strong> of properties built in the UK are custom build, more than a third of Britons are open to building their own home.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The research also shows that access to mortgage finance is now the single biggest barrier to owning a home among first time buyers, rising above raising a deposit for the first time since 2012.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now <strong>57%</strong> of these buyers say that getting a mortgage is the most difficult hurdle to overcome, compared to <strong>41%</strong> in June 2014 and <strong>33%</strong> in September last year. Difficulty in accessing finance for home movers has been marginally less striking, rising from <strong>42%</strong> in September 2013 to <strong>51%</strong> in September 2014.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/survey-reveals-opposition-to-big-housing-developments-in-uk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rental demand on the up</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/rental-demand-on-the-up/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/rental-demand-on-the-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 08:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5836</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; A new report from the UK’s largest letting agent – Countrywide – has shown that demand for rental property across Britain has continued to grow over the last 12 months.  In fact the data shows that there are now five tenants chasing every available rental property, up from 4.2 in August 2013. &#160; The [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5838" alt="Discount Landlord " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/18th-Sept.jpg" width="435" height="326" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A new report from the UK’s largest letting agent – Countrywide – has shown that demand for rental property across Britain has <strong>continued to grow</strong> over the last 12 months.  In fact the data shows that there are now <strong>five tenants</strong> chasing every available rental property, up from <strong>4.2</strong> in August 2013.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The increased demand is also reflected in rental values.  In August, <strong>15%</strong> of properties let for more than the asking price, a figure which rises to <strong>19%</strong> in London where competition between tenants remains fierce.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-5836"></span></p>
<p>In August, the average rent value in the UK passed the<strong> £900 per month</strong> barrier for the first time, an increase of £13 per month from July.  Over the past 12 months, average rents have increased 5.1%, rising twice as quickly as the equivalent period last year.  As is often the case, London has led the way with properties in zones 2-6 seeing the most growth.</p>
<p>In a sign that landlords are responding to market trends, tenants are signing up to increasing longer tenancies with record numbers choosing to remain in their property by renewing their contract.  Every region of the UK, with the exception of Central London, saw the length of the average tenancy rise to stand at an average of just over 16 months.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Commenting on the report, Nick Dunning, group commercial director at Countrywide Lettings said: “The gradual cooling of the sales market over the past 1-2 months means we have begun to see upward pressure on rents, driven by a rise in demand from tenants with fewer leaving the sector.  An increasing number of landlords have been able to re-let their property at a higher rate with tenants willing to meet and in some cases surpass rising asking prices.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Need specialist landlord insurance? Call <strong>Discount Landlord</strong> on <strong>0800 294 4522</strong> today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/rental-demand-on-the-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Landlords face eviction problems after failing to protect deposits</title>
		<link>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/over-a-third-of-landlords-face-eviction-problems-after-failing-to-protect-deposits/</link>
		<comments>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/over-a-third-of-landlords-face-eviction-problems-after-failing-to-protect-deposits/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marketing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Landlord Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landlords and Tenants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenancy Deposit Protection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/?p=5825</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; As many as 38% of landlords wishing to evict have not protected the tenant’s deposit in accordance with deposit protection rules introduced in 2007, according to Landlord Action. &#160; There is still a major problem with amateur landlords – and even some agents – understanding deposit legislation, says the eviction specialists, who have been [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5827" alt="Discount Landlord " src="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/16th-Sept.jpg" width="435" height="291" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As many as <strong>38%</strong> of landlords wishing to evict have not protected the tenant’s deposit in accordance with deposit protection rules introduced in 2007, according to Landlord Action.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is still a major problem with amateur landlords – and even some agents – <strong>understanding deposit legislation</strong>, says the eviction specialists, who have been reviewing enquiries from the start of the year.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-5825"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Unless the tenant’s deposit is protected in a legally-recognised protection scheme within 30 days, and the tenant is sent the relevant information, the <strong>landlord could face a penalty of up to three times the value of the deposit</strong>, which is then awarded to the tenant.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Adding tension to the relationship between landlords and their agents, landlords could also face penalties if their agent failed to comply with the legislation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“There are too many landlords that still do not know enough about being a landlord and their responsibilities. Many are falling to comply with deposit protection rules and this is having a knock-on effect when landlords wish to evict through section 21. The simple fact is, ignorance will not solve this problem,” says <strong>Paul Shamplina</strong>, founder of Landlord Action.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A court order for possession is the only way a landlord can legally evict a tenant who will not move out voluntarily (and who is in rent arrears or in breach of their tenancy agreement), but in order to obtain this, a landlord must first return the deposit.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Landlord Action says that the number of calls from desperate landlords who are being sued by their tenants for not protecting the deposit is increasing greatly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“It seems to me, that tenants are becoming savvier than landlords when it comes to buy to let legislation. Landlords, this is your business, you must be fully versed in your responsibilities,” said Shamplina.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Eddie Hooker, CEO of MyDeposits</strong>, said: “The findings of Landlord Action are somewhat worrying, especially as all three schemes have seen a healthy year on year increase in the number of deposits being protected. Having said that, we should not become complacent and there is clearly more work to be done in ensuring that deposit protection is embraced by the entire private rented sector.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>Get all the latest advice for landlords, in the </i><a href="https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/landlord_zone"><i>Landlord </i><i>Zone</i></a><i> section of our website.</i><i></i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.discountlandlord.co.uk/news/landlords-and-tenants/landlord-insurance/over-a-third-of-landlords-face-eviction-problems-after-failing-to-protect-deposits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
